Methods are functions that belong to classes,
which are frameworks for objects.
Though classes are not part of this exam,
for us to understand the role of a class and
the importance of testing methods for those
classes, let’s look at a brief code example
defining a class and then an object within
that class.
In this 533-methods file, I have a class called
Game_Player, which starts on line 1.
Again, classes are not on the exam, but to
understand method testing, we at least need
to know what a class is and what it does.
This class defines an initial object, starting
on line 2, which contains a character and
a score for a game, and then on lines 3 and
4, we see two properties for the character,
name, and score.
The get_score function on line 5 uses the
character we defined on lines 2 through 4
and then has an interval, set to 10, that
when the code on line 6 runs, the player’s
score increases 10 points, and then the score
is returned so that it can be used in code
later if needed.
On line 9, we initiate an instance of a game
player and name the player Robin.
Then, on lines 10 and 11, we run the get score
method on Robin to add the default value,
10, to Robin’s score and then again to add
100 points to the score.
Again, for a test to be successful, we need
to know the expected outcome before we run
said test.
I have the expected results in commented code
on lines 10 and 11.
First, we should see 10 as a score.
Then, on line 11, we override the default
interval of 10 and add 100 to Robin’s score,
so the total at that point should be 110.
I will run this code, and we will get the
expected results of 10 and 110.
You may not work with classes right away in
Python, but as you continue to learn this
language, you eventually will, and for that
reason, you need to know how to test methods,
which are functions inside of classes, to
ensure they work as a single class could be
used once, several times, or thousands of
times in code and we want these classes to
do what their intentions are each time we
call upon them in code.